我叫巴里·艾伦  是现今世上速度最快的人
My name is Barry Allen, and I am the fastest man alive.
我年幼时
When I was a child,
看到自己的母亲被令人难以置信的东西杀害
I saw my mother killed by something impossible.
巴里  快跑
Run, Barry, run!
我父亲因为谋杀母亲进了监狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但我秘密地用自己的速度打击犯罪
but secretly, I use my speed to fight crime
寻找跟我一样的人
and find others like me.
终有一天  我会找到杀害母亲的凶手
And one day, I'll find who killed my mother...
妈妈
Mom!
让我父亲沉冤得雪
And get justice for my father.
我就是  闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on The Flash...
是克莱德·马登
It's Clyde Mardon.
我觉得他能操控天气
I think he can control the weather.
我还以为不会有人像我这样
I didn't think there was anyone else like me.
我才不像你  你是杀人犯
I'm not like you. You're a murderer.
我爱你  爱瑞丝
I love you, Iris.
他和我只是好朋友
He and I are just best friends.
我连追都追不上他  要怎么才能抓住他
So how do we catch somebody that even I can't keep up with?
我们可以造一个电子屏障
We can fashion an electronic barrier
来困住逆闪电
to trap the Reverse-Flash.
超级电容器
The super capacitors,
牢笼正在波动
the containment field is fluctuating.
我还是不知道为什么囚禁系统失败了
I still don't know why the containment system failed.
我一定是漏了什么
I must have missed something.
你认为威尔斯博士杀了巴里的妈妈吗
You think Dr. Wells killed Barry's mom?
现在还不知道
I don't know yet,
但我知道威尔斯的确藏有秘密
but I do know that Wells keeps secrets,
也许这是其中之一
and this may be one of them.
一年前
我要去赶飞机了
I got a plane to catch!
快过来  克莱德
Come on, Clyde!
我去
Damn it.
我觉得我好像打中了其中一个
I think I got one of them.
你的运气迟早会用光的  弟弟
Your luck's gonna run out one of these days, little brother.
你从我十岁的时候就这么说了  马克
You've been telling me that since I was ten, Mark.
因为我从你十岁时就开始照顾你了
Because I've been taking care of you since you were ten.
听着  马上会很颠簸
Look, it's gonna get choppy.
你也许想要系上安全带
You might want to strap yourself in.
你就是忍不住  对吧
You just can't help yourself, can you?
哦天啊
Oh, my God.
克莱德
Clyde.
闪电侠  第一季  第十五集
今天
我从没想到你是爱打保龄球的那类人
I never would've pegged you as someone who likes to bowl.
这是世界上我最喜欢的地方之一
Oh, this is one of my favorite places in the world,
而且我觉得这是为数不多的
and I'm guessing one of the only sports
我可以秒杀你的运动项目
that I can destroy you at.
好吧  你确定吗
Oh, okay, you think so, huh?
我很确定
I'm pretty sure, yeah.
好吧
Okay.
嗨  你们好
Hi, guys.
爱瑞丝  艾迪  你们好
Iris, Eddie, hey.
你们在这儿干嘛呢
What are you guys doing here?
我们觉得这会很有趣
We thought it would be fun.
巴里和我从小就在这儿打保龄球了
Barry and I have been bowling here since we were kids.
不如和我们一起玩吧
Why don't you guys join us?
我们不想破坏你们的约会
We don't want to interrupt your date.
不会的  没关系的
No, it's--it's okay.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
当然啦  会很好玩的
Of course. It'll be fun.
第二球补中
你闻到什么了吗  巴里  那是失败的味道
Do you smell that, Barry? That's defeat.
你从没告诉过我你那么喜欢保龄球
You never told me you were such a big fan of bowling.
我当然有
Sure I have.
这是世界上我最喜欢的地方之一
This is one of my favorite places in the world.
我很佩服啊  艾伦
I am impressed, Allen.
我听说主人正想卖掉这地方
I heard the owner was thinking of selling.
也许你可以给这地方写篇文章
Maybe you could write a piece on the place?
我还在纠结保龄球算不算运动项目
Um, I'm still iffy on whether bowling is an actual sport.
我也在想这个问题
I've wondered the same.
不过无论这是项运动还是爱好  我都比你强
Well, sport or hobby, I am still better than you.
好吧  我是认真的  来点新闻报道
All right, well, I'm serious, a little bit of press,
也许道路就会被规划
the lanes could be designated
这可能变成地标性建筑什么的
as, like, a landmark or something.
艾迪  该你了  伙计
Oh, Eddie, you're up, man.
好的
Oh, right.
加油  宝贝
Go get 'em, babe.
开始录音
Recording start.
中城验尸报告  文档编号28527
Central City coroner's report, file 28527.
嘴唇黏膜和口腔内部
Petechial hemorrhaging in the mucosa of the lips
均有点状皮下出血
and the interior of the mouth,
强烈的漂白剂气味
the strong odor of bleach,
以及死后绑扎痕迹
and the presence of a postmortem ligature mark
都暗示着死者的死因是
all suggest the decedent's manner of death, is--
谋杀
homicide.
有什么我能帮到你的吗
Can I help you?
是的  你能帮我
Yes, you can.
我想要知道是谁杀了克莱德·马登
I want to know who killed Clyde Mardon.
他在六个多月前被一名警察射中
He was shot by a cop a little over six months ago,
我想要知道他的名字
and I want his name.
这是机密信息
That's privileged information.
我需要请你离开了
I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
真可惜
Shame.
求你了
Please.
告诉我警察的名字  现在
Cop's name. Now.
我一年做上百份的尸检
I perform hundreds of autopsies a year.
也许这个可以唤起你的记忆
Perhaps this will jog your memory.
巴斯特·基顿  这家伙是个天才
Oh, Buster Keaton. That guy was a genius.
-是的  -我不敢相信你没看过这部电影
- Yup. - I can't believe you've never seen this movie.
一定是我出生前的作品
Must have been before my time.
我得给你份必看电影名单  马上就写
I gotta make you a must-see movie list, pronto.
请一定写  虽然我非常开心
Please do. While I am more than happy
能和你看一晚上的老电影  西斯科
to spend an evening watching old movies with you, Cisco,
但你不是要参加你哥哥的晚宴吗
do you not have your brother's dinner to attend?
是的  我本想邀请凯特琳和我一起去
Yeah. I was gonna ask Caitlin to come with me,
但我想到了更好的主意
but then I got a much better idea.
那是什么
Which was?
根本不去
To not go at all.
你家里的情况好些了吗
Things are not any better with your family?
你要错过电影了
You're missing the movie.
是啊
Right.
算了  我实话实说吧
Okay, you know what, I' m gonna be honest with you.
事情反而非常好
Things have actually been pretty fantastic...
自从我不常去看他们之后
since I stopped seeing them so much.
中城停尸房的安全警报被触发了
Silent alarm has been tripped at the Central City Morgue.
为什么会有人想抢劫停尸房呢
Why would anyone want to rob a morgue?
我得走了  停尸房有紧急情况
I got to go. Emergency at the morgue.
-再见  -家里见
- Bye. - See you at home.
琳达  对不起  我也该走了
Hey, Linda, sorry, I should go too.
他们会需要取证室的人
They're going to need someone from the crime lab.
回见
I'll see you.
刚还蛮有意思的
Well, um...that was fun.
是啊
Yeah.
出租车  出租车
Taxi! Taxi!
别这样  我要迟到了
Oh, come on, I'm gonna be late!
怎么回事  你看到了什么
What's going on? What do you see?
一具死尸
A dead body.
巴里  你在停尸房
Barry, you're in a morgue.
你要再详细一点
You're gonna have to be a little more specific than that.
是法医  他死了
The coroner, he's dead.
市长已经把此案列为头等大事了
The mayor's made this high priority.
收到  队长
Copy that, captain.
艾伦  这是我未婚夫刚买的
Allen, my fiance just bought me this!
真对不起  队长
Yeah, I'm so sorry, captain.
帮乔找出谁是凶手
Just help Joe find out who did this.
为什么这里都是水
What's with all the water?
这里的喷水系统坏了还是怎样
Did the sprinkler system go off or something?
不是  我查过所有的喷水器  都完好无损
No, I checked all the sprinklers. They're all intact.
但看看这个
But look at this.
这是什么  冰吗
What is that, ice?
在法医身上有好几个淤青
The coroner has multiple impact bruises on his torso,
都是网球状大小
all the size of a tennis ball.
通过地上水和冰的量来看
Judging by the amount of ice and water on the ground,
我猜他是因冰雹致死
I'm guessing he was killed by hail.
冰雹  在这里
Hail? In here?
对
Yeah.
你觉得是史纳特干的吗
Do you think this was Snart?
不是  他的冷冻枪不会做到这样
No, his cold-gun couldn't have done this.
乔  我找到点线索
Joe, we got something.
法医办公室正好装了
The Coroner's office just installed
自动录音系统
an automated dictation system.
听听看这个
Listen to this.
拜托  不要再打了
Please, no more.
等你告诉我了  我再停
I'll stop when you tell me...
等等
Stop.
是谁杀了他
Who killed him?
我知道这个声音  那是马登
I know that voice. That's Mardon.
-我要知道是谁  -克莱德·马登死了
- I want a name. - Clyde Mardon's dead.
不是克莱德·马登  是他哥哥  马克
It's not Clyde Mardon. It's his brother, Mark.
是韦斯特警探
It was Detective West.
是他射中了他  乔·韦斯特警探杀了你弟弟
He shot him. Detective Joe West killed your brother.
他会为他的所作所为付出代价
He will pay for what he did.
所以克莱德·马登有个哥哥
So Clyde Mardon has a brother?
两兄弟都在坠机事件中活下来了
And both brothers survived the plane crash,
然后粒子加速器爆炸
and then the dark matter released
释放出的黑暗物质
from the particle accelerator explosion
本质上以同样的方式影响了他们
affects them both in virtually the same way.
对  只是马克的能力看上去更精准
Yeah, only Mark's powers seem to be a lot more precise.
能像那样在室内控制天气
To be able to control the weather like that, indoors?
你得是个天气巫师
You'd have to be a Weather Wizard.
我从最开始就想用这个名字了
Ooh, been waiting since week one to use that one.
三叉神经性头疼
Trigeminal headache?
-什么  -三叉神经性头疼
- What? - Trigeminal headache.
脑子冻冰
Brain freeze.
那你为什么不直接说脑子冻冰呢
Then why don't you just call it a brain freeze?
我想这次你反方向跑出个旋风
So I'm guessing you running around a twister in the opposite direction
也不能解决问题了
isn't gonna to do the trick this time.
我刚想起来  在我们和马登速跑那次
I just remembered. During our run-in with Mardon,
克莱德·马登  我当时在做一件
Clyde Mardon, I was tinkering with something
能吸引无束缚的空气电子的东西
to help attract unbound atmospheric electrons.
就好像接地装置
Like a grounding mechanism?
对  因为马登能操控天气的
Yes, 'cause the only way
唯一办法
that Mardon can control the weather...
就是如果他可以接入大气中的
is if he can tap into the atmosphere's
自然电子回路
natural electrical circuit,
如果我们拿走这个回路  就是晴天
and if we take away that circuit, clear skies.
辛格在问情况了  我该走了
Singh's checking in. I gotta go.
我们晚点警局见
Yeah, I'll meet you at the station.
乔  我们会找到马登的  别担心
Joe, We'll find Mardon. Don't worry.
完全不担心
I'm not worried at all.
不得不说  他对于被一个来复仇的
Well, he's taking being targeted
超能力者追杀这件事表现得非常淡定
by a revenge-seeking meta-human rather well, I must say.
别担心  巴里  我保证乔会没事的
Don't worry, Barry. Joe will be fine, I promise.
是  我知道
Yeah, no, I know.
我其实想跟你聊点别的事
I actually wanted to talk to you about something else.
昨晚  我在去停尸房的路上
Look, last night, on my way to the morgue,
我看到了些东西
I saw something.
你看到什么
What'd you see?
我在跑  然后我转身看到了我自己
I was running and I turned and I saw myself.
我不知道  或许是另一个闪电侠在我身边跑
Or I don't know, another Flash running beside me.
有意思
Interesting.
对  你觉得那是什么
Yeah. What do you think it was?
可能是视觉错觉  一种由
Could be an optical illusion, a mirroring effect
风切和灯光引起的镜面效果
caused by wind shear and light,
可能是速度导致的海市蜃楼
a speed mirage, if you will.
看上去不像  它...
It didn't seem like that. It was...
他看上去很真实
He seemed real.
这样吧  我们先着重找到马登
I tell you what. Let's focus on finding Mardon,
等到把他安全关在管道监狱之后
and once he's safely contained in the Pipeline,
我们再详细调查此事
we'll investigate this.
中城警局
马登的案子查的怎么样
Where are we at with Mardon?
没人在停尸房听到或看到什么
No one at the morgue saw or heard anything.
我们在细查相关同事
We're canvassing known associates,
看他是不是找了其他人
seeing if he reached out to anybody.
也许可以找到他藏在哪里的线索
Maybe can get a lead on where he's holed up.
好  我们为什么不让斯旺来查
All right, why don't we let Thawne do that?
因为我对马登兄弟的了解比任何人都多
Because nobody knows the Mardon brothers better than I do.
查尔和我追踪他们很多年了
I mean, Chyre and I tracked them for years.
我知道他们的思考模式
I know how they think.
所以你更应该
Which is why you should coordinate
留守这里协调调查
the investigation from here.
如果你们俩想留住她的笑容
If you guys want to keep that smile on that pretty face,
那就什么都不要告诉她
she doesn't hear about any of this.
亲爱的
Hey, sweetheart.
爸爸
Hey, Dad.
你们都在忙什么
So, what are you guys working on?
你们有没有好线索对一个诚实的记者说的啊
You got any good leads for an honest reporter?
现在都挺风平浪静的
Things are actually pretty quiet around here right now.
你们能让我们聊聊吗
Can you guys give me a minute?
好  我和巴里正要去吃午饭
Yeah, me and Barry were actually gonna go grab lunch.
是吗
We were?
对  对
Right, yeah, yeah.
自从昨晚
Ever since last night,
你就没怎么说话  怎么了
you've barely said a peep. What is going on?
我不太喜欢昨晚
I didn't like the way I felt
我看到你和巴里的相处模式
watching you and Barry last night.
艾迪  巴里他
Eddie, Barry, he's just--
我懂  就像家人一样
Like family. I know,
而且我知道在我之前你俩有很多回忆
and I know you two have a long history that pre-dates me,
但是爱瑞丝  我们现在住一起
but Iris, we live together.
你是我女朋友
You're my girlfriend,
希望有一天  你不只是女朋友
and someday, hopefully, you'll be more.
我不喜欢感觉每次你跟巴里在一起
I don't like feeling like the odd man out
我都是尴尬的存在
every time you and Barry are together.
而我也不应该那样
and I shouldn't have to.
艾迪  巴里永远都是我生活中的一部分
Eddie, Barry is always gonna be a part of my life.
我明白  但是我觉得你们之间有些不一样了
I get that, but something's changed between you two.
不管是什么  都让我很不舒服
Whatever that is, I am not okay with it.
我已经好久都没吃过这个了
I haven't had one of those in way too long.
感觉不错
Felt appropriate.
你想谈谈你最近发生的事吗
So, you want to talk about what's been going on with you?
你觉得我最近发生什么事了  巴里
What do you think's been going on with me, Barry?
我们要对付的人很棘手
You just seem a bit cavalier,
可你看起来却有点漫不经心
considering what we're up against.
我们没要对付什么人
We aren't up against anything.
乔  拜托  我...
Joe, come on, I--
我没事
Look, I'm fine.
能换个话题吗
Can we just change the subject, please?
好吧
Sure.
其实  我可以听取一下你的建议
Actually, you know, I could use some advice.
关于什么的
About what?
你知道的  就是感情方面的
Uh, you know, just relationship stuff.
你是指跟那个叫琳达的姑娘吗
Oh, you mean, like, that girl, Linda?
不是  其实是跟爱瑞丝
No, actually. With Iris.
我们之间的关系又开始变得有点复杂
Things between us have gotten a little complicated...again.
你在向你的养父询问
You're asking your adopted father
关于你爱上了他女儿的建议
for advice about being in love with his daughter,
而他的女儿正在和他的搭档交往
who just so happens to be dating his partner?
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
事情已经不止是复杂了
Things have gone way past complicated.
有时候  我和爱瑞丝会有那种瞬间
Sometimes, me and Iris have these moments,
就是当我看着她的双眼
and when I'm looking into her eyes,
很难不去认为
it's hard not to think
她对我也有同样的情意
that she's feeling the same way I do.
你已经告诉爱瑞丝你对她的感觉了
Look, you already told Iris how you feel,
只要她没回应你
so unless she comes out and says she feels the same way,
你能做的就只有珍惜那种时刻了
all you can do is hold on to those moments.
开始下雨了
Man, it is coming down.
是啊
Yeah.
中城美好的一天又开始了
And it's another beautiful day here in Central City.
万里无云
Not a cloud.
是马登
Mardon.
在抓住马登之前  你不许离开警区
You're confined to the precinct until Mardon's caught.
大卫  是你自己说过的
David, you said it yourself.
那个狗杂种杀了我的搭档
That son of a bitch killed my partner.
我已经失去弗雷德·夏尔  不能再失去你了
And I'm not gonna lose you the way I lost Fred Chyre.
我没法阻止你发怒  乔
Look, I can't stop you being pissed, Joe,
但起码我能保证你的安全
but I can keep you safe.
也许你女儿可以联系到闪电侠
Maybe your daughter can contact The Flash.
我不想把她牵扯进来
I'm not getting her involved in this.
艾伦  别让他到处乱跑
Allen, make sure he doesn't go anywhere.
我得离开这里
I need to be out there.
乔  当我头脑不清醒的时候
Joe, you're always the first one
你总是第一个站出来提醒我
to tell me when I'm not thinking clearly.
我能抓住克莱德  我也一样
I took down Clyde. I can take down
能抓住他那个垃圾哥哥
his dirt bag brother too.
那件事不是你一人为之的  还记得吗
You didn't do that alone, remember?
你说得对
You're right.
这些人要怎样才能保护我
How are any of these guys going to protect me?
他们不知道  不知道马登的能力
They don't know. They don't know what Mardon's capable of.
好吧  幸运的是
All right, well, lucky for you,
你那些尖端科研实验室的朋友们知道
your friends at S.T.A.R. Labs do.
"闪电侠  以极速闯入我们的生活"
"The Flash: Speeding his way into our lives?"
有点太骚气了  不是吗
That's a little on the nose, don't you think?
我有东西要给你看
I want to show you something.
西蒙·斯塔格  记得他吗
Simon Stagg. Remember him?
已经有大概半年没见到他了
Hasn't been seen in, like, six months.
我记得传说他是位隐士
I thought the rumor was he was a recluse.
像霍华德·休斯那样的
You know, went all Howard Hughes.
这张照片是斯塔格失踪那晚被拍下的
This was taken the night that Stagg went missing.
斯塔格失踪那晚最后一个离开
The last person to leave Stagg Industries
斯塔格工业的人是哈里森·威尔斯
the night that Stagg disappeared was Harrison Wells.
这说明不了什么的  梅森
This doesn't prove anything, Mason.
这已经足够支持我展开推测的了
It's enough for me to develop a theory.
这文件里每一个线索都指向一个人
Every trail in this files leads to one person,
哈里森·威尔斯
Harrison Wells,
所以我需要你去问问
which is why I need for you to start asking
你那些认识他的朋友们  爱瑞丝
your friends who know him some questions, Iris.
琳达
Linda.
好啊
Hi.
昨晚挺有意思的
Last night was fun.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
我想跟你道个歉
Look, I just wanted to apologize.
为了什么
Apologize...?
为打扰了你和巴里约会
Well, for interrupting your date with Barry.
我不应该那样做...
I shouldn't have done that...
对不起
and I'm sorry.
爱瑞丝
You know, Iris,
当你对我说巴里对你有感觉的时候
when you told me that Barry had feelings for you,
我以为这是那种典型的女人之间
I thought it was just the typical weird crap
会说的奇怪的胡话
that women do to each other,
但昨晚  我意识到一些你没说的事
but last night, I realized what you didn't tell me,
这让我有点恼火
and what's kind of irritating
那就是你对他也有感觉
is that you have feelings for him too.
不  琳达  不是那样的
N-no, Linda, I mean, it's not like that.
在这里工作会学到一点  爱瑞丝
One thing you learn about people when you work here, Iris,
那就是  没说出来的可能才是真实的
it's usually what isn't said that's the real story.
在电话里你的声音听起来好像
So it sounded like something was kind of bothering you
有点烦恼  有什么事吗
on the phone. Is everything all right?
没事  挺好的
Yeah, it's fine.
那晚挺有意思的  是吧
So the other night was fun, right?
是啊  艾迪玩得开心吗
Yeah. Did Eddie have a good time?
是的  琳达呢
Yeah. Linda?
我想是吧
I think so.
你不觉得我们太...  那个了吧
You don't think we were too...you know.
没有
No.
那就好
Okay, good.
我给你打电话是因为  报社那个所谓的顾问
So the reason that I called you was because my sort of advisor
总是在给我上课
at the paper is always teaching me lessons,
一些行业技巧  怎么才能弄到好题材
tricks of the trade, how to get good story,
还有一件事  他反复在对我说
and one of the things he's repeatedly telling me
那就是跟着你的直觉走  看它会指向哪里
is to follow your hunch, see where it leads.
这建议听起来不错
Sounds like good advice.
是的  没错
Yeah, it is.
但是这一次  那个直觉和你有关
Except in this instance, that hunch involves you.
你可以问我任何事  爱瑞丝
Well, you can ask me anything, Iris.
是关于哈里森·威尔斯的
It's about Harrison Wells.
他怎么了
What about him?
我是说  过去的一年中城
Well, I mean, a lot of strange things
发生了很多奇怪的事
have been happening in Central City this past year.
闪电侠  火人  有人相继失踪
The Flash, the Burning Man, people going missing.
斯塔格失踪那晚
He was there at Stagg's office
他就在斯塔格的办公室里
the night that Stagg went missing.
你认为威尔斯博士应该为此事负责吗
And you think that Doctor Wells is what, responsible?
我几乎不认识他  但是你和你的朋友了解他
I mean, I don't really know him, but you and your friends do.
巴里  在你内心深处  是否曾想过
Barry, in your heart of hearts, do you think it's possible
在哈里森身上
that there's more to Harrison
还有很多不为人知的事
than people have been led to believe?
哈里森·威尔斯是个好人
Harrison Wells is a good man.
如果你要爆料
If you're looking for a story,
那你在他身上是找不到料的
then you're not gonna find one with him.
我称之为天气魔棒
I call it the Wizard's Wand.
精妙  要怎么用
Subtle. How does it work?
想象它是支激活状态的避雷针
Think of it like an active lightning rod.
只要指向天上  魔棒就会像海绵般
You just point it at the sky, and it'll suck up
吸收四处飘动的能量
whatever energy's floating around it like a sponge.
魔棒会阻止马登吗
And it'll stop Mardon?
肯定能降低他的速度
It'll certainly slow him down.
如果他没有可用的大气电子
If there's no atmospheric electrons available to him,
就没办法控制天气
there's no way for him to control the weather.
干得漂亮  西斯科  一如既往
Good work, Cisco, as always.
抱歉失陪了  我要去舒展一下我的腿
If you excuse me, I'm gonna go stretch my legs.
没事吧  你好像有点心不在焉
You okay? You seem a little off.
没事  没事  有人...
Yeah, yeah. Uh, somebody at...
《中城新闻图报》里有人告诉爱瑞丝
Somebody at Picture News got it into Iris's head
威尔斯博士有可疑情况
that something suspicious is going on with Dr. Wells.
比如说呢
Like what?
比如说他知道西蒙·斯塔格发生了什么事
That he knows what happened to Simon Stagg.
显然  自从那晚我阻止了丹东·布莱克后
Apparently, nobody's heard from him or seen him
就再也没有人有他的消息了
since the night I stopped Danton Black.
你怎么和她说的
What'd you tell her?
说她弄错了
That she's wrong.
她的确是弄错了
And she is.
放在身边
Keep this handy.
魔棒会保护你不被马登的力量所伤
It'll protect you from Mardon's powers.
真理  自由  正义
好  西斯科  我知道了
Yeah, Cisco, I got it.
乔  我知道你现在有很多事要处理
Hey, Joe... I know you got a lot going on right now,
可你提到过威尔斯博士
but... you mentioned Doctor Wells
可能和巴里妈妈的死有关
might have had something to do with Barry's mother's murder.
你为什么会这么想
Why did you think that?
不重要了  我弄错了
Oh, it doesn't matter. I was wrong.
但是你当时好像很肯定
But you seemed really sure of it.
西斯科  我现在没空和你说这件事
Look, Cisco, I can't talk about this right now, okay?
正在拨打  巴里·艾伦
听说你在找我
I heard you were looking for me.
我来了
Here I am.
马登
Mardon.
你好啊  乔
Hey, Joe.
我能叫你乔吧
I can call you Joe, can't I?
看到你对我弟弟胸口开了两枪
Figured we don't got to be too formal
我想我们不必太见外了
seeing as you put two bullets in my brother's chest.
你弟弟杀了我的搭档
Your brother killed my partner
还有很多无辜的人
and a whole lot of innocent people,
甚至威胁要杀更多的人
and threatened to kill even more.
克莱德的确不是圣人  但他是我的家人
Yeah, Clyde was no saint, but he was family.
如果无法保护家人
If you can't protect your family,
那至少能为他们报仇
the least you can do is avenge 'em.
这是你我之间的事
This is between us.
没必要伤害其他人
Nobody else needs to get hurt.
但是他们会受到伤害的
But they are gonna get hurt.
乔
Joe!
别过来
No!
我不会这么轻易被你打倒的  乔
I'm not gonna be so easy to put down, Joe.
拿下他
Take him down!
不  快跑
No, run!
乔
Joe!
队长
Captain!
大卫
David.
西斯科  我要回家了
All right, Cisco, I'm heading home.
西斯科
Cisco?
好吧好吧  我会和你
All right, fine, I will watch
一起看每一集《行尸走肉》的
every episode of The Walking Dead with you.
你没办法阻止马登袭击警局的
You couldn't have stopped Mardon from attacking the police station.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
我不是在想这件事
No, that's not it.
你怎么看威尔斯博士
What do you think of Dr. Wells?
-什么意思  -我是说你是否觉得
- What do you mean? - I mean, do you think
他有能力做坏事
he's capable of doing something bad?
这是因为巴里说自己听说了一些事吗
Is this because of what Barry said he heard?
自从粒子加速器爆炸后
Ever since the particle accelerator exploded,
总是有人找威尔斯博士的茬
there's always someone who's got it in for Dr. Wells.
不不  不止这样  乔说也许
No, no, it's more than that. Joe said that maybe
威尔斯博士可能
Dr. Wells was somehow involved
和巴里妈妈的死有关  他可能杀了她
in of Barry's Mother's death and her murder.
那很荒谬
That's absurd.
我知道  我也是这么说的
Yeah, I know, and that's what I said,
我们也证明了事实不是这样
and we proved that that wasn't the case,
但我只是说说而已  有些事不对劲
but I'm just saying, some things aren't adding up.
比如说呢
Like what, for example?
过来  看看这个
Come here, look at this.
那晚我们在力场困住了逆闪电
The night we trapped the Reverse-Flash in the force-field,
然后因为囚禁系统失败  他逃脱了
he escaped because the containment system failed,
但是我检查了三次数据库
but I checked that data three times,
在他逃离的时候  超级电容器
and the super-capacitors were still fully charged
临界警报
仍然是充满电的
when he got out.
超级电容器阵列状态报告
数据有出入  凯特琳
The numbers don't add up, Caitlin.
囚禁系统没理由会失败的
There's no reason that the containment system should have failed.
我相信这当中一定有合理的解释
I'm sure there's a perfectly good explanation.
其中一个合理的解释就是
One perfectly good explanation
威尔斯对陷阱做了手脚
is that Wells did something to the trap.
你是在说威尔斯博士
Are you suggesting that Dr. Wells is in league
和黄衣人勾结吗
with The Man in the Yellow Suit?
那晚我们都看到那人差一点杀了他
We all saw that thing nearly kill him that night.
没错  差一点
Yeah, nearly.
西斯科  你说的话毫无道理
Cisco, what you're saying doesn't make any sense.
简直是疯了
That's crazy.
明早你能拖住威尔斯不让他进尖端科研实验室吗
Can you keep Wells out of S.T.A.R. Labs tomorrow morning?
-谢谢你  巴里  -没事
- Thank you, Barry. - Yeah.
我没想过会在这种情况下见到大卫的同事
This isn't how I thought I'd finally meet David's co-workers.
他对你赞赏有加
He speaks very highly of you.
真的吗
Really?
大卫光说不做
David's all bark.
而且声音还不小呢
A very loud bark.
他怎么样了  医生
How is he, doctor?
我们让他的情况稳定下来了
We're stabilizing him.
他的下肢正处于麻痹状态
He's experiencing some paralysis in his lower extremities.
天呐
Oh, my God.
现在最难估计的是
The hardest thing to gauge right now
他的神经系统识别障碍程度
is the extent of his neurocognitive deficits.
他可能不再是你们所认识的那个人了
So he may not be the same person you remember.
我能见见他吗
Can I see him?
对不起  只有亲属才能探望
I'm sorry, visitation's for family only.
他的未婚夫就是他的家人  医生
Being his fiance makes him family, doctor.
当然
Uh, sure.
他还能回归警队吗
Will he be able to return to the force?
其实我不确定他是否能再次走路
I'm actually not sure he'll be able to walk again.
乔  你要去哪
Joe, where are you going?
我要结束这一切
I need to end this.
你不能一个人去
Not by yourself.
没错  我就是要一个人去  我了解他
Yes, by myself! I know him!
我可以找到他
I can find him.
我不想还有其他人受伤
I don't want anybody else getting hurt,
尤其是你和爱瑞丝
especially Iris and you.
爱瑞丝没事...
Iris is fi--
马登说他会为他弟弟报仇
Mardon said he was going to avenge his brother.
那就不只是找我寻仇了
That goes beyond me.
他会找上你和她的
It goes all the way to you and her.
你跟爱瑞丝待在一起  保证她的安全
You stay with Iris, and you keep her safe.
不要离开她身边
Do not leave her side.
行  好的
Yeah, all right.
你们看到爱瑞丝·韦斯特了吗
Hey, have you seen Iris West?
她去找她爸爸了
She went to see her dad.
-你是巴里·艾伦  对吗  -是的
- You're Barry Allen, right? - Yeah.
他的朋友兼哥哥  或者说是哥哥兼朋友
Her friend/brother? Or is that brother/friend?
说是朋友就可以了
Friend is fine.
我是梅森·布里奇
Oh. I'm Mason Bridge.
就是你认为
Oh, you're the guy who thinks
哈里森·威尔斯是个疯狂的天才吗
Harrison Wells is some mad genius?
不不  我从没说过他是个疯子
Oh, no, no, no, I never said he was crazy.
他是个反社会者及骗子  这是肯定的
He's a sociopath and a liar, for sure.
-真的吗  -你没发现吗
- Really? - You don't see it?
你们在一起相处这么久
All the time you two spend together.
什么意思
Excuse me?
我无聊的时候  就跟踪他
Sometimes when I'm bored, I follow him around.
大部分时间  他都是一个人
And for the most part, he keeps to himself,
除了跟你见面
except when he's meeting up with you,
这点倒是有点频繁
which he seems to do quite a bit.
然后有一次  他跟西蒙·斯塔格见面
And then one time, he met up with Simon Stagg,
之后噗的一下  西蒙·斯塔格消失了
And then poof, no more Simon Stagg.
所以你是说威尔斯知道斯塔格在哪吗
So you're saying Wells knows where Stagg is?
不是  我是说威尔斯杀了他
No, I'm saying Wells killed him.
好吧  即便我相信你说的
All right, well, even if I believed you,
其实我是不相信的
which I don't,
但他坐在轮椅上
he's in a wheelchair.
他怎么可能做到那个
How could he possibly have done that?
我的一份加密电子文件里有证据
I have evidence in a secure digital file
可以解释这一切
that will explain everything.
什么证据
What--what evidence?
你在周日的报纸上就可以看到了
You'll just have to read about it in the Sunday paper,
跟其他人一样
like everybody else.
让我看看你能不能告诉我
Let's see if you can tell me
那天晚上到底是哪里出了错
what really went wrong that night.
乔
Joe.
艾迪  你不该来这
Eddie. You shouldn't be here.
你也不该自己来追捕马登  搭档
And you shouldn't be chasing after Mardon alone, partner.
有什么发现吗
You find anything?
还没
Not yet,
但这是马登兄弟六年前的藏身处
but this was an old Mardon brothers' hideout about six years ago,
所以这只是我大胆的猜测
so it's a long shot.
但听着  艾迪...
But listen, Eddie--
省了吧  我不会走的
Save it. I'm not leaving.
你有爸爸的消息吗  他没接手机
Hey, have you heard from Dad? He's not answering his cell.
没有
No.
我没跟他联系过
I haven't talked to him.
我开始有点担心他了
I'm starting to worry about him.
你这么早回家干嘛
What are you doing home so early?
其实  我在找你
I was looking for you, actually.
我刚见到你的朋友梅森了
I just met your friend Mason,
他说他有某种证据证明
and he said he had some kind of proof
威尔斯博士做了某件事
that Dr. Wells did something.
你知道是什么证据吗
Do you know what it is?
不知道  他没告诉过我
No, he hasn't told me.
好吧
All right.
你跟琳达怎么样了
So, how are things going with Linda?
你干嘛这么说
Why do you say it like that?
怎么说了
Like what?
就像你之前经常这么说"贝姬·库珀"一样
Like how you used to always say "Becky Cooper."
得了吧
Oh, come on.
作为高中女友  贝姬·库珀真是个噩梦
Becky Cooper was a nightmare of a high school girlfriend,
你根本就不该跟她约会
and you should have never dated her.
好吧  你是说琳达跟贝姬是一类的吗
Okay, so you're saying that Linda is "Becky" material?
我不会这么说
I mean, I wouldn't go that far.
她很性感  人好又聪明
She's...hot and nice and smart
工作也干得好
and she is really good at her job.
我只是...
I just...
我认为她不是适合你的人
I don't think that she's the right one for you.
那谁是
Then who is?
所有系统运转正常
什么
What?
我不明白
I don't understand.
这不可能啊
This doesn't make any sense.
刚刚有人在这
Somebody was here very recently.
连环凶手克莱德·马登死了
他留下这个给我看的
He left this here for me.
接下来去哪
Where to next?
乔
Joe!
你只摔断了条腿  算是个奇迹了  乔
Small miracle you only broke the one leg, Joe.
我从飞机上被吸出来那晚
The night I got sucked out of my plane,
基本上全身的骨头都断了
I broke almost every bone in my body.
太受折磨了
It was excruciating.
你至少尝到了一点我受的苦头
At least you got a small taste of what that felt like.
但是
Still...
我想你永远都不会知道
Guess you'll never know
当上帝是怎样一种感觉
what it really feels like to be God.
在我杀你弟弟之前
That's what your brother said to me,
他就是这么对我说的
right before I killed him.
杀你我不需要这些超能力
I don't need these powers to end your life.
那就动手吧
Then do it.
你来这就是为了这个  不是吗
That's what you came here for, isn't it?
以牙还牙
An eye for an eye?
乔
Oh, Joe.
我要的可远不止这个
I want so much more than an eye.
我总是忘记
I often forget how important it is
改变一下我现有的日常规律有多重要
to step away from my ever present routine.
谢谢你  凯特琳
Thank you, Caitlin.
今天早上真是让我的日常节奏焕然一新
This morning has been a refreshing change of pace.
你的早餐不必只是两个煮鸡蛋
You can have more than two hard-boiled eggs for breakfast,
威尔斯博士
Dr. Wells.
我能怎么说呢
What can I say?
我想我是习惯的奴隶吧
I guess I'm a creature of habit.
抱歉  我还以为这个是打包带走的
Oh, I'm sorry, I believe these were to-go.
其实  我想我们可以
Actually, I thought we could
坐在这慢慢享受它们
sit here and enjoy them.
为什么不呢
Why not?
我们已经知道马登的能耐了
We've seen what Mardon can do,
但不要忘记
but do not forget,
他不是无敌的
he is not invincible.
他同样是个人
He is still a man,
我真不敢相信发生了这样的事
I can't believe this is happening.
至多  是个罪犯
at best, a criminal.
我们会找到他的
We'll find him.
我们会找到这个垃圾
We will find this dirt bag...
看着我  好吗
Hey, look at me, all right?
我保证我会把他带回你身边的
I promise I will bring him back to you.
你们需要做的是
Whatever you need to do...
好
Okay.
我需要你们搜寻整座城市
I want you all to scour this city
直到我们找到乔为止
until we find Joe.
行动吧
Move out!
你爸爸在我手上
I have your father.
他受了点伤  但还活着
He's a little broken, but still alive.
如果你还想要他继续活着的话
If you want him to stay that way,
来滨水区  南边
come to the Waterfront, south side.
还有爱瑞丝  你要是报警的话
Oh, and Iris, you tell the police,
你爸就死定了
your father's dead.
她马上就来
She's on her way.
他抓了我爸爸
He has my dad.
他说如果我告诉任何人  他就杀了他
He says if I tell anyone, he'll kill him.
他想让我去滨水区见他
He wants me to meet him at the Waterfront.
-好吧  我和你一起去  -好
- All right, I'm coming with you. - Okay.
走吧
Let's go.
巴里
Barry.
我能和你说句话吗
Can I talk to you for a second?
琳达  抱歉  我现在没时间
No, Linda, I'm sorry, I really can't right now.
当然了
Of course not.
不是那样的  是有急事
Look, it's not like that, it's an emergency.
我得马上走了
I have to go right now.
你知道  威尔斯博士  我只是...
You know, Dr. Wells, I just...
我想再谢谢你一次
I want to thank you again
为了你为罗尼所做的一切
for all that you've done for Ronnie.
感谢一次就足够了
One thank you will suffice, I'm sure.
你知道吗  凯特琳  如果西斯科调整
You know, Caitlin, if Cisco were to adjust
尖端科研实验室卫星的径向速度参数
the radial velocity parameters on the S.T.A.R Labs satellite,
我们没准能更好地侦测形成风暴的漩涡
we might be able to better detect the vortex of a forming storm,
如果我们能够侦测那些上升气流
and if we could detect those air updrafts,
不管起源地在哪  不管有多小
no matter where they originate, no matter how small,
我们没准能找到马克·马登
we might be able to locate Mark Mardon.
这点子真棒
That's a great idea.
那咱们不如去尖端实验室告诉西斯科吧
So why don't we go to S.T.A.R. Labs and alert Cisco?
让我先把这些打包
Let me just get these to-go.
能把这些装进外带杯子吗
Hi, could I get these in to-go cups?
好的  请等一会
Sure, just a second.
你理解不了我的目标
My goals are beyond your understanding.
威尔斯博士  我们终于见面了
Dr. Wells, we meet at last.
你理解不了我的目标
My goals are beyond your understanding.
真不敢相信
I can't believe this.
我可与闪电侠不同
Oh, I'm not like The Flash at all.
可以说我们是相反的
Some would say, I'm the Reverse.
恭喜你  乔  今天你是我的陪客
Congratulations, Joe. You're my plus-one today.
前排观看你爱的所有人
Front row seats to watch everyone
和所有事物  被毁灭
and everything you ever loved destroyed.
那漂亮女孩儿也要死
Pretty girl too.
真是可惜了
Such a shame.
求你了  她是我女儿
Please, she's my daughter.
克莱德是我的兄弟
Clyde was my brother.
他是个小偷还是杀人凶手
He's a thief and a murderer.
她可是个无辜的女孩
She's an innocent girl.
那就由她为他父亲的罪恶还债吧
She'll pay for the sins of the father then.
马克
Mark--
他们都要付出代价
They'll all pay.
你相当的聪明  西斯科
You're incredibly clever, Cisco.
我总是这么说
I've always said so.
你就是他
You're him.
逆闪电
The Reverse-Flash.
我还从没真正的正式地向你介绍过自己
You and I have never been truly, properly introduced.
我  是艾尔伯德·斯旺
I am Eobard Thawne.
斯旺
Thawne?
和艾迪一样
Like Eddie.
他算是位远亲吧
Let's call him a distant relative.
我们抓住逆闪电的那晚
The night that we trapped the Reverse-Flash,
你差点死了
you almost died.
那里有两个你
There were two of you.
那只是个残像
It's an after-image,
极速幻象  也可以这么叫
A speed mirage, if you will.
乔是对的
Joe was right.
那晚你在那里
You were there that night,
十五年前  在巴里的家中
15 years ago, in Barry's house.
你杀了诺拉·艾伦
You killed Nora Allen.
我本来并没有想杀死诺拉
It was never my intention to kill Nora.
我是去杀巴里的
I was there to kill Barry.
为什么
Why?
你是他的朋友
You're his friend.
你一直在教他如何...
You've been teaching him how to--
跑得更快  我知道  这只是种手段
Go faster, I know. A means to an end.
我会告诉你为什么
And I'll tell you why.
因为我被困在这里
Because I have been stuck here,
被囚禁在了这破地方
marooned here in this place
长达十五年之久
for 15 long years.
而闪电侠  还有闪电侠的速度
And The Flash and The Flash's speed
是我
is the key
回到我原本的世界
to my returning to my world.
原本时间的关键
To my time.
没有人可以阻止这件事发生
And no one is going to prevent that from happening.
我可以帮助你
I can help you.
你很聪明  西斯科
You're smart, Cisco.
但你还不够聪明
But you're not that smart.
你知道
Do you know
对你们隐瞒这些事有多难吗
how hard it has been to keep all of this from you,
尤其是对你  因为说实话
especially from you? Because the truth is,
我已经有点喜欢上你了
I've grown quite fond of you.
而从很多方面  你带给了我
And in many ways, you have shown me
一种儿子的感觉
what it's like to have a son.
原谅我
Forgive me,
但对我而言  你已经死了几个世纪了
but to me, you've been dead for centuries.
我们怎么办
What do we do?
他会找到我们的
He'll find us.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
爱瑞丝  你得离开这里  好吗
Iris, you need to get out of here, okay?
你必须离这里越远越好
You need to get as far away from here as possible.
-我不会离开你的  -爱瑞丝  求你了
- I am not leaving you. - Iris, please!
听我说  自从那晚
Listen to me, ever since the night
你告诉我你的感觉之后
that you told me how you felt,
我就没有停止想过你
I have not been able to stop thinking about you.
一开始  我非常生气
At first, I was really mad,
然后我发现之所以我不能停止想你
and then I realized that the reason that I couldn't stop thinking about you
是因为我不想停
was because I didn't want to.
我从没停止过想你
I've never stopped thinking about you.
凯特琳
Caitlin.
巴里  我得和你谈谈
Barry, I need to talk to you.
威尔斯博士  他没...
Dr. Wells, he isn't--
现在没时间说这个  好吗
Hey, there's no time for that right now, all right?
正有一个大海啸冲向城市呢
There is a tsunami heading for the city.
我怎么才能阻止它
How do I stop it?
理论上  如果你能沿着海岸线
Theoretically, if you can create a vortex barrier
创造一个旋风屏障  也就是一股风墙
along the coastline, a wall of wind,
那没准能够在海啸击中城市之前
that would be able to sap the tidal wave of its energy
抵消它的能量
before it hits the city.
这需要前后跑
By running back and forth.
要跑多快
How fast?
我不知道你能不能跑那么快
I don't know if you can run that fast.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
我不想以这种方式让你知道
I didn't want you to find out this way.
快跑
Go!
出租车  出租车
Taxi! Taxi!
别这样  我要迟到了
Oh, come on, I'm gonna be late.
天呐
Oh, boy.